In the last lecture we added the logic to add ingredients,
Son dersin ieriini eklemek mantmz vard.
now of course I also want to do the opposite and remove them. I already added the removeIngredientHandler
imdi elbette tm bunlar yapmak ve bunlar kaldrmak istiyorum zaten burger oluturucu
to the burger builder container,
konteyner kaldrmak madde handler ekledi.
now we need to fill that with some life.
imdi babamn hayatyla doldurmamz lazm.
The logic is pretty similar to the logic we had in the addIngredientHandler,
Mantk, sahip olduumuz manta ve ADD madde ileyicisine olduka benzemektedir.
it's basically just the opposite,
Temel olarak tam tersi.
deducting an ingredient.
Bir maddenin peindeyim.
So I will copy the code for now, add it here.
Bu nedenle, burada eklenen kodu kopyalayacam.
I'm interested in the old count, the updatedCount is the oldCount minus one, updatedIngredients
Eski saymla ilgileniyorum Gncelleme hesab eski Kontak eksi bir gncel malzemeler.
still follows the same logic here and the same for the price, though it's of course not a price addition,
Tabii ayn mantkla ayn felsefenin aynsn ve fiyatn izliyorsa da tabii ki fiyat indirimi
it's a price deduction which I then also want to deduct here and not add,
artc deil, daha sonra buradan den ve eklememek iin olan veren dction.
and that actually is all.
Ve aslnda hepsi bu.
So I simply reduce my ingredient count by 1 and I deduct the price.
Dolaysyla sadece Ingrediance'imi 1 azaltrm ve fiyat derim.
Now with that, we're updating the ingredients and the price again
imdi bununla malzemeleri ve fiyat tekrar gncelleyeceiz.
let's now go back to or let's now
imdi geri dnelim ya da alarz.
pass this method handler, this method reference here,
Gemi ise Methot ileyici Methot bavurusu burada.
this event handler,
Bu olay ileyicisi.
let's pass it down to build controls.
Kontrolleri oluturmak iin aaya geelim.
So there I want to have the ingredientRemove prop where I pass the reference to this method we
Dolaysyla burada Propp'u kaldrp burada baz mant ekleyen ve Ingredion zellii
just added some logic to and this ingredient remove property here can be used inside build controls
kaldrlan bu yntemin bavurusunu yalnzca bu iki denetimi de ierecek ekilde kullanmasn istiyorum.
now, where I not only want to have added on the individual build control but also removed and here, I'll then go and
imdi yalnzca bireysel yap denetimine eklemeyi deil ayn zamanda kaldrlan yerleik idam edilmi
executed an arrow function where I simply execute ingreidientRemoved and passed the type of the ingredient
okla ileve sahip olduum yerde Ingredion'u kaldrp ayn mantn ardndan karlmas
which should be removed, following the same logic
gereken bileen trn de getim.
as for the addition.
Ekleme gelince.
Now we need to hook up the remove property in the individual build control and there on the less button,
imdi bireysel yap denetiminde kaldrma zelliini balamamz ve orada son dme zerinde olmas gerekiyor
I'll therefore add an onClick listener too and simply execute props removed or not executed, pass a
ve bu nedenle tklama dinleyicisini eklemek ve yalnzca pervanenin kaldrlm ya da altrlmamasn altrmak
reference to that
iin bir bavuru gnderin.
remove props which holds a reference to that method
Bu yntemle ilgili referans ieren pervaneleri karn.
we want to execute so that once the button is clicked and this event is fired,
Dmeye tklandnda ve bu olay tetiklendiinde isteklerle altrlmak istiyoruz.
we execute that method.
Bu yntemi uyguluyoruz.
With that let's save this and let's see if that works,
Bununla birlikte, bunu saklayalm ve ie yarayp yarayp yaramadn grelim.
let's add salad and bacon and let's remove bacon and salad and cheese.
Biraz pastrma ekleyelim ve pastrmay, salata ve peyniri karalm.
Now we have a problem if we start deducting elements we don't have though, we get an error then and it
imdi elimizde olmayan bir eyi terk etmeye balarsak bir hata yaparz, ancak o zaman
makes sense because we tried to remove an ingredient which we don't have.
bir hata yaparz ve mantkldr nk sahip olmadmz bir maddeyi kaldrmaya altk.
So our burger builder here, the state becomes negative,
Devlet olduunuz burger reticimiz negatif olur.
we have -1 bacon and that throws an error
Eksi 1 pastrma var ve bu gerekten bir hata.
because we can't create an array to render from a negative value.
nk negatif bir deer oluturmak iin bir dizi oluturabiliriz.
So we should fine tune our removeIngredientHandler by also checking if we do have ingredients to begin
Bu nedenle, karc reaktif ileyicimiz Belz ile balayacak ieriklerimiz olup olmadn kontrol ederek
with.
bulmalyz.
So the old count of a given ingredient
Belirli bir bileenden eski saymak da yle.
should be greater than zero.
Sfrdan byk olmaldr.
So if old count is smaller or equal than 0, then I essentially want to return so that nothing happens
Eski saym Ciro'dan daha kk veya eitse, esas olarak geri dnmek istiyorum, bylece hibir ey olmaz.
if we try to reduce an ingredient which we don't have. So now if I click on salad or bacon or anything
u an sahip olmadmz bir maddeyi okumaya alrsak, aslnda satmaya baladm, pastrma
else, nothing happens.
veya hibir ey olmaz.
Of course it would be even better if the button would be disabled then
Tabii dme devre d braklrsa daha da iyi olurdu.
so let's introduce that logic too. There,
O halde orada bu mant tantalm.
I want to pass some information about which button should be enabled and which button should be disabled
Hangi dmenin etkinletirilecei ve yap denetimlerim iin hangi dmenin devre d braklmas gerektiine ilikin
to my build controls.
baz bilgileri iletmek istiyorum.
For that let's scroll down to the render method
Dalat iin render yntemine kaydrn.
and before we return jsx, I will create a new constant which I'll name disableInfo and there, I simply
Ve J'yi X olarak dndrmeden nce, yeni bir sabit sava ad devre d brakma info
want to create a new object where I will distribute the properties of this.state.
oluturacam ve orada yalnzca bu devletin zelliklerini datacak yeni bir nesne oluturmak istiyorum.
ingredients,
Malzemeler.
keep in mind, this.state.ingredients simply is this object,
Bu madde ieriini basite bu nesne olarak aklnzda bulundurun.
so I basically copied it in an immutable way.
Yani temelde deimez bir ekilde kopyaladm.
Now this object alone is of course not all the information I want,
imdi sadece bu nesne elbette istediim tm bilgiler deil.
now I'll create a for/in loop so loop through all the keys in disableInfo and it will simply check if this
d tm anahtarlar zerinden dng ve sadece Ciro veya daha az olup olmadn kontrol edecek ve bilgi anahtar devre d brakmak iin gncellenir.
is zero or less and it will update the disableInfo key,
imdi devre d brakmak iin bir for dngs oluturun bylece devre
so salad, meat and so on with that information of that check, so that the object will not have the shape
Bylece Sallet eti ve benzeri bilgilerle birlikte, eer nesne ekli
of salad, 0 meat, 0
yukar hcreden 0'a gelmeyecekse bu 0' karlar.
but simply if it should be disabled or not. So salad,
Ama basite devre d braklmal ya da salam olamazsa.
true,
Doru.
meat, true and true will be the value which is assigned if it should be disabled.
Gerek ve gerek, devre d brakldysa atanan deer olacaktr.
So we will check if disableInfo for a given key is smaller or equal than zero
Bylece belirli bir anahtar iin devre d brakma arsnn sfrdan kk veya sfra eit olup olmadn kontrol eder.
because keep in mind, disableInfo key is the value of each key,
Aklda tutarak bu gl bilgi anahtar her bir anahtarn deeridir.
so zero in all these cases at the start, and this check here will turn true or false.
Bu nedenle bataki tm bu durumlarda sfr ve burada kontrol doru mu yoksa yanl m yapar.
So we will update this in our copied object, not in the original one,
Bu yzden kopyalanan nesnemizde orijinali deil de gncelleneceiz.
the copied one with true or false.
Kopyalanan kii doru veya yanl.
Now with that, we can pass the disableInfo, the disableInfo to the build controls component here.
imdi bununla birlikte, devre d brakma bilgisi devre d braklm bilgi iin yapm denetimi bileenine yaptrabiliriz.
So there I will set a disable property and pass disabledInfo.
Bylece engelli bir mlk ayarlayp devre d braklm bilgileri gnderirim.
Now of course you should take advantage of this disabled property in this build controls component
imdi elbette bu yap denetim bileenindeki bu devre d braklm zelliin avantajlarndan yararlanmalsnz ve
and there we should pass this information to the individual build control, to let it know if it should
bu bilgileri bu dmeyi devre d brakp brakmamaya alp almamas gerektiini bildirmek iin tek
disable that button or not.
tek yap denetimine geirmemiz gerekir.
So I will set a disabled property there too
Bu yzden orada da zrl bir mal varl ayarlayacam.
and for that, I will use the disabledInfo I am getting on the disabled prop of build controls, not build
Ve bunun iin devre d brakmak iin alyorum zrl bilgileri kullanacam kontrol ina denetimleri
control, build controls
ina denetimleri pervane.
I'm using in the burger builder container, and there I now of course want to access the disabledInformation
Burger oluturucu kapsaycsnda kullanyorum ve orada elbette belirli bir denetim tr iin devre d
for a given control type
braklm bilgilere erimek istiyorum.
because keep in mind that the structure of disabledInfo is basically of that form, salad,
Unutmayn ki bu abled bilgi yap temelde bu form katdr.
true, meat false and so on.
Gerek et der vb.
So this is what we'll have in this restructured object
Yani bu yeniden yaplandrlm nesnede sahip olacamz ey budur.
and if it's true, it should be disabled,
Ve eer doruysa devre d braklmaldr.
so what we need is we need to access the information for a given type of control and thankfully we of
Buna ihtiya duyduumuz ey, belirli bir denetim tr iin bilgiye erimek zorunda olduumuz ve
course know that type in build controls because we're looping through controls where we store that type
elbette denetim denetiminde hibir veri tr deil, nk eleri ekleme ve kaldrma iin
which we also use for adding and removing elements
kullandmz bu tre depoladmz kontroller araclyla dng yapyoruz.
but here also to access the right disabledInfo. And with that, we can use the disabled prop in the individual
Ama burada ayrca devre d braklm bilgi yazmak iin eriebilir ve son dmeyi devre d brakmak
build control to disable the less button and disabled is a default property we can set on a html button
iin bireysel yap denetiminde devre d braklm Propp'u kullanabilir ve devre d braklm bir HCM dmesi esinde ayarlayabileceimiz varsaylan bir
element
zelliktir.
and of course I want to set it equal to props.disabled,
Ve elbette onu pervane engelli olarak ayarlamak istiyorum.
so either to true or to false,
Yani ya doruya veya yanla.
and I will restructure this all over multiple lines to make it a bit easier to read.
Okumak biraz daha kolay hale getirmek iin bunu birden fazla satra gre yeniden yapacam.
So I hope the logic is clear here,
Bu yzden buradaki mantk aktr umarm.
we're simply making sure that the less button gets disabled if the ingredient is at zero or less.
Bileen Ciro ya da daha dkse, daha az dmenin devre d kalmasn salamaya alyoruz.
So now you see all the buttons are blocked,
imdi tm dmeleri engellediini gryorsunuz.
the styling is set up because it was part of that css file I shared with you,
Tarzn ayarlanmas, dosyalar sizinle paylald iin bu C-lerin bir parasyd.
and once we start adding an ingredient, we can click the button again.
Ve bir kez bir madde eklemeye baladktan sonra dmeyi tekrar tklayabiliriz.
So that's our build controls working,
te bu bizim tekne kontrollerimiz alyor.
let's also output the price now.
imdi fiyat da verelim.